i hear a pig man
but i don't see a pig man oh he's up
there what are you doing
how did
i'm confused because you come out of
this portal which means you by yourself
walked all the way up there
anyway hello my name is green and
welcome back to another hermitcraft
episode let's get rid of this little
piggy
and today we're doing more work on the
base but something's happened obviously
my
pufferfish missing posters have done
something because
this little guy appeared here
but look it's not actually paul it's
pull
so
i don't know if this is the original one
or someone's just pulling a little joke
pull it pulling a little joke on me
i don't know if someone's pulling a joke
on me right now but i don't know where
the original pool is or if this was the
original pool and they've renamed him to
pull i just don't know anymore i don't
know you're probably wondering where
codswallop is well he was in there with
the fish but i've put him in here for
now because if you have two of them in
that little area there they're gonna
push each other out and we're just gonna
end up with more tears anyway what we're
doing today is a lot of work to the base
i have been preparing stuff
and oh boy oh boy we've got another
blender well another blender layer to
this big
modern cake or this big
giant coffee cup whatever you want to
call it but we're gonna try and remove
the idea of the coffee cup because
you'll see i've added these things here
actually speaking of trying to fly
around and show you stuff someone's left
me and i think it was ixiai azume aviord
uh he's left me this little thing that's
like
giving me some hints and tips and stuff
so this is drink when flying when
looking at the base and this is slow
falling there's he gave me silk touch
and he told me to use an ender chest as
a backpack so he's giving me some handy
things i kind of already knew those
i just play old school
so let's see if this works
drink the potion of slow falling and oh
my goodness
yes he's so right
you can't you can't
you can still go fast forward but as
soon as you stop
you just you're able to look at the base
oh this is going to be brilliant so as
you can see i've lined out exactly where
these towers are going to be and all i
need to do now
is actually build these up all the way
equal to here because i think that's
actually going to be three layers and
you can see
i've actually put three of them here in
a triangle formation well as close to a
triangle
as possible
so let's give that a go shall we wow
this slow falling thing is
okay as soon as you actually want to go
down
and then it's a bit
then it's then it's not so good when you
actually want to hit the floor not so
good
and we're coming in for a landing
so what we're going to do is build these
up all the way up to the top and that
means a lot of blocks are going to be
done so i think we're going to probably
time lapse this little bit to get it
done as quick as possible and i'll
probably answer a couple of q a
questions as well all right let's get on
with it so the first question is from mr
makistein himself what minecraft feature
would be your biggest wish
well i try not to think too hard about
it because i really like what they're
coming up with i'll tell you what i
would like to see less of is zombies the
drowned and the husks they're all zombie
variations i am much more inclined to
say i really wish for more mobs that are
unique like the phantom
than more zombie variations
cub fan 135 says what's something you've
always wanted to do but haven't done yet
well i've always wanted to learn
woodwork or pottery and i've tried both
of them but i haven't actually been able
to master them yet because my time is
always spent working but if that's
something i'd like to do
fork draws says why don't you go mining
that's because in every single episode
of hermitcraft i usually spend one to
three days recording and whenever i run
out materials or anything like that i do
all the grinding stuff off camera
because it's not entertaining even if
i'm just talking about things i prefer
there to be a bit more action in my
videos so even though it doesn't look
like i've got mining trust me uh there
are many hours of mining done in the
background
peter davies says what are some of the
future projects for architects now
that's a team started by me involving me
and mumbo now we're both still in the
process of setting up our bases and
stuff but there might be a pretty cool
project coming out in the next few
episodes that may indeed be our first
one but we're still in the process of
getting stuff together so for the moment
just remember that we're on it and demi
saying says how's the cupcake flower pot
coming along well why don't we go and
see for ourselves
after that time lapse i actually ran out
of resources fairly quickly
but i didn't really stop i went on the
grind and i kept going
and kept going
and kept going and i think i've made
just about the most progress i've ever
made in a single episode
look at that i even have added the other
two towers and i made a bit more
progress adding in these little support
beams i'm clearly not finished yet but
i think it's looking a lot less like a
blender now for sure
this is looking really really cool i'm
get i'm very happy with how this is
going i've seen a couple of comments
over the series so far saying that this
looks bad and i should abandon it but
i'm definitely not giving up on this
not at all i think this looks really
cool i think it looks really unique and
i think by the time it gets to the full
height that it's going to be this is
going to be really really unique and
something special now remember
this is way out of my comfort zone okay
like i never ever build futuristic at
all
so this is this is just new to me
entirely i've added this water elevator
in here which kind of just skips the
middle layer because this is where i'm
working at the moment but i'm really
happy with how everything's going now i
was a little bit unsure especially when
i saw comments saying that they didn't
really like it but i think overall i'm
gonna continue with this and keep going
now the reason i have built this out of
concrete powder instead of
making it out of white concrete is
because
i have to manually change all of the
concrete powder into concrete itself
we're using water i thought to myself
why not save myself a lot of time by
making it out of concrete powder and
then coming up here to the top
and then just drooping over water like
so and letting it go all the way down
and it's going to change it all to
concrete as it flows down you can see it
slowly changing
so i thought this was a really clever
way of saving time
although it will get rid of all the
torches at the bottom when it eventually
gets down i mean look it hasn't even
reached the bottom yet that gives you an
idea of just how high up we are this is
a really really big build so let's take
a little look now that i've transformed
this entire one
into concrete yep it's looking pretty
good obviously there's a bit of concrete
powder there it definitely looks a lot
more solid
and there's still water dripping down
that's just gonna take a little while
but yeah this is looking really cool and
let me show you what the first layer
looks like now down here is still kind
of like the basement i guess this is
where i've got all my working stuff
but up here we get a real taste for the
first layer and how clean it why is
there a dirt block there all that's oh
that's awful why is there a dirt block
there anyway you get a good idea for how
sort of clean it's going to be in here
once it's all smoothed up so obviously
all of that's going to become more
smooth all of this going to be cleaned
up and then you'll get an idea for the
decent amount of space in here i'm not
even sure that this is going to stay i'm
probably going to move these water
elevators inside the towers to make them
more useful
and yeah i'm just i'm really pleased
with how this has come out it's a decent
amount of space in here and i'm going to
be able to use this for all of my
various ideas
i also had a little idea for a prank
that we can play on mumbo jumbo i've got
all the materials and i think i'm gonna
do it right now ah so on this island
this is where he's currently going to
what
someone's got a load of pixel art on his
base
this can't be mumbo can it
this mumbo wouldn't have done this oh
this ice
do you
do you smell that
there's a prank going on here
what has gone on
looks like
it looks like they've all got mustaches
they're all characters with very
distinct mustache oh my goodness how
long
did this take them pixel art takes a lot
of time
at the best of times but making them in
mid air that big look at all the
resources that went into this the detail
oh
i've got a tear in my eye these these
pranksters they're pro they're pro this
you know what this is going to make my
little prank seem absolutely stupid
oh my goodness what is this so there's a
little star like this is it looks like a
hollywood star mumbo and then there's a
mustache
and then there's a thing here
oh my goodness so yeah cub fan
is the perpetrator of this by the looks
of things maybe scar got involved as
well
i guess if you want to know what this is
all about you can go and have a look at
that i know i'm gonna have a look i
don't even know if i should do my prank
because it's gonna be so feeble in
comparison nah we're still gonna do it
we're still gonna do it
what we're gonna do is a don't touch the
red button prank okay but it's not
actually a button but this is gonna play
on people's curiosity okay
what we're gonna do is dig a big hole a
really big hole
i just had a quick thought i don't even
know if this trick works in this version
so let's give it a shot shall we so
this is a trick that i've known for a
long time where you get basically double
height grass or flowers
and then you put sand on the top and
then it floats
or
or doesn't float
huh
and then
well there i've just made a hole for no
reason
oh my goodness
now that is really bad that i'm glad
that i didn't dig too much because
it doesn't work
it doesn't work at all
that trick seems to no longer be a thing
oh dear
i've got myself into a pickle now i
think we should probably
cover this up
and pretend
that nothing has happened
at all
nothing has happened at all maybe i can
figure out a different way for this to
work i might even go do a little bit of
experimenting there must be a way of
doing it but my old trick doesn't work
and i don't know what to do about it
oh dear
not not okay
good as new
kinda
oh this is so sad
this is a really sad day that we can't
actually make sand float anymore that's
really disappointing
well we'll have to think of something
else now
huh
i'm still convinced there's got to be a
way of doing it before what you would do
is have too high
of grass or a flower or whatever then
you'd put sand on the top you'd delete
this one and it wouldn't update this top
block meaning that the sand would float
unfortunately it seems that that's just
not gonna happen anymore
so i think maybe we might have to
abandon this at least it doesn't look
like i've made too much of a mess i've
changed the island slightly but i doubt
he'll even notice to be honest with you
i guess we'll just fly back in shame
i'm of a bit of a loss to what to do now
i'm feeling particularly mischievous
there's nothing more infuriating than
having a trap in your mind and then
realizing that it's not gonna work and
that was a waste of time
however if you look on the tablet you'll
see that
x
i
s-u-m-a
is afk
now you know how i feel about afk people
now going back to 2016 i uploaded a
video about how to mess with afk players
now i have been on the server now for
quite some time and he has been afk for
quite some time i even went on a little
reconnaissance mission to find out where
he is and i now know where he is he's at
his sea temple base
so i'm hoping that he has not got his
elytra on and we're gonna send him on a
little trip here we are this is his base
it looks like he's
he's making some progress we need to
make sure that he's not going to notice
so i did actually make a bit of noise
around him to see if he would do
anything but it looks like he didn't he
has got his elytra on him meaning he can
just fly back very easily
but this should be a bit of a surprise
nonetheless
we're gonna have to break a little bit
of his base but
oh
that's death that's death that's death
that's death that's death
this is gonna be a little harder than i
thought oh oh he's there oh
dear
um this is so why does everything i do
fail today uh let's bail
let's bail real quick
abort abort mission abort mission
oh my plan has fallen through
we now we better go and repair that
because that's not odd we can't leave a
hole in the base
okay we fixed the base let's go let's
get out of here
ah
it's gonna be a long time before
someone's afk for that long
ah well we're back in the base
and now back to the drawing board
actually i need a drawing board i need a
prank drawing board so that i can come
up with new ideas
nothing seems to be working
one thing that i'm actually lacking
quite a lot especially when i'm in my
mischievous mood
is tnt
now no one's selling tnt at the moment
and that's an issue for me so i was
thinking once i get this top layer done
this might be high enough to create a
very miniature version of a mob farm the
same one in fact
that tango's made maybe we'll fly over
there and i can show you what i mean
here it is this is his this is his mob
farm and it's absolutely brilliant in
the way that it works
and i love it i think it's really clever
now what i was thinking is i don't have
space for something this big but i can't
see any reason why i can't have one of
these machines in here one of these
spawning platforms to just
ever so slowly because i spend so much
time on my base ever so slowly produce
the resources that i need and it's so
clever whenever enough mobs spawn here i
think what it does is it spawns water
which pushes them over the edge they
land
in here
i don't know if it will do it for me but
they they will get pushed over the edge
into here where they they die from the
magma blocks and they can't get out and
then i
i think that there's a collection system
underneath and it all gets sucked into
one giant
system i think if i was going to make
something like this i'd definitely have
to watch a tutorial because i have no
idea what's going on here to be honest
with you
ah another day
another afk
so jevin impulse and zuma are all afk
and jevin in particular has been
standing here for a very very long time
like over an hour so i feel pretty safe
as i've made a lot of noise around him
look
he's gone he's not here let's push him
outside
if can we push him outside oh this is
gonna take ages isn't it
okay jeff jeff
we're going outside buddy we're going to
go for a little walk there's got to be
an easier way to push someone we're
almost out the door jevin
we're almost there i've got to do is get
him on one of these blocks
and we will be good to go
i need a lot more time i need him to be
afk for at least another hour for this
to be worth it
oh my goodness this is gonna be funny
okay so we need to go one two
three
and then
oh come on
no
no please don't ruin this for me
i need to defend jevin
oh he's stuck
he might be after jevin
oh i'm so lucky
oh my goodness i'm so lucky that could
have ruined everything
oh i just realized if he's been afk for
a long time chances are phantoms are
gonna get him this trap is deadly now
oh well we'll still continue and we
place a sticky piston here if my maths
is correct and if this still works the
way i hope it does if i place a redstone
block here there we go
we're snagging we've got a snag we got a
snag i forgot to get rid of this oh
we need a we need to there we go okay
we're attached on multiple places now
hopefully when i remove this obsidian
block he's gonna go
on a little journey wait that's gonna
snag
learn from your mistakes green okay
hopefully
hey
oh
oh he's taking damage
oh no he's taking damage oh no what do i
do what do i do what do i do what do i
do what do i do
fail prank fail prank fail prank
i need to do something i need to be able
to fly slower
all right i'm gonna go in for the same
for the same for the sake
what when
i saved him no
where did the obsidian block go oh it's
in my hand
he's going to die if i continue this
i can't get up on it
oh this is a disaster
i'm on it i'm on it i'm on it
oh i fixed it maybe we should just send
him on his way
onwards
somewhere else
uh how high are we we're at 179.
there's a chance that he will hit a
[Music]
dox flying around trying to spy on me he
totally deserved that
i'm thinking
we just now that he's high enough
because i don't know how much health
jevon has now
this is this is a really scary thing i
don't i'm not this was i thought this
was a good idea but i didn't i don't
want anyone getting hurt this is meant
to be a harmless prank but apparently
it's totally totally not so let's
rearrange this and send him onwards and
we can follow him for a little while and
see what happens hopefully this goes
well
hopefully it goes well
thank goodness yeah jevin is properly
afk i am a proper noob at this this is
not fast work at all
remove the obsidian block
and hopefully
go away he
goes
bye gevin
bye bye gemin
oh this is great
bye buddy
uh i have a couple of responsibilities
now that i've done this
one i really hope that jevin is gonna
come back soon because
well
there's a likelihood that he will
eventually die i'm gonna have to look
after him now my responsibility is gonna
have to be to follow him around a bit
because i don't want him to die and it's
just about to get night time i'm pretty
sure he has phantoms on him i am at 900
sure he has phantoms on him
so we're gonna sleep and then we're
gonna follow him about and make sure he
doesn't get into any trouble and see how
long this goes on for
it's still going to take jevin a while i
feel
i wonder how much we really need to look
after him to be honest i think as long
as it's daytime he's going to be fine
this is ridiculous jevin learn never to
go afk again love you buddy right let's
just go straight for a while at the same
y coordinate that he's at
and hopefully we'll see that he's not
gonna hit anything
i've gone quite a few hundred blocks
away and it seems like he is going to be
absolutely fine for the time being it
honestly depends how long he's gonna go
afk for
the one thing we need to make sure of is
that we keep sleeping
and keep the phantoms away from him
what no jevin
how did jevin fell off
uh oh
oh no this isn't good
if we find the machine we'll know
exactly where he dropped i can't even
find it
i can't even find the machine oh there
is
it didn't get very far
right let's swoop in and stop this
machine
there we go it stopped
okay
bad idea green never do this again
failed attempt
we need to go
and find out where he died
what no what my elytra
oh
goodness
my electro just didn't go
it was over by the ship i know that much
this is a disaster
this is a proper disaster ah
there we go
okay
this must be jevon's right okay we might
not have found jevin's stuff yet okay
now we need to go and find jevins he
would have fallen
somewhere just around
here maybe
ah oh
oh my god oh i found it
oh
oh thank goodness we found this ex him
losing xp is not a big deal because
we've got so many farms for that kind of
stuff now
oh my goodness
jevin i hope
oh you didn't deserve this buddy
okay no harm no foul we got the stuff
i guess we gotta leave a sign because
he's gonna be confused why he died in
the middle of nowhere
oh
i am really ashamed of this i'm really
ashamed this has been an absolute
failure of a prank day i'm guessing the
lag is what caused this so i'm guessing
what happened was the pushing machine
slime block machine lagged and that's
the same reason i couldn't open my
elytra when i was falling
so i'm guessing lag happened it just
took that little extra nudge he got
caught up inside the blocks
and then pushed over the
ah
so annoying
i think we need to do a cover-up now
i think i think we don't admit what we
did okay okay okay damage control he
doesn't know what happened okay he
doesn't know what happened i think we
should do a major cover-up here hi jevin
looks like you had an accident don't
worry i got your stuff so there's his
stuff no harm no foul right and i don't
even think i'm gonna sign it from me i
don't want the trail on me at all he
might i don't know how he's going to
suss it out i need to go and patch up
the hole that i made quickly and
hopefully jevin would just think that
this was a weird experience he won't
expect anything at all right right there
were no eyewitnesses doc was a witness
he saw me oh well if this is gonna
definitely come back to bite me i just
want everyone to know right now i didn't
expect him to die i never ever prank
with the expectation of killing people
in this game i was just trying to send
him a long way away and i thought he'd
be safe but lag kills people more than i
do well that was a total failure
but
a lot of you have been wondering what's
been happening to the game of tag that's
been going on in the server well as far
as i'm aware someone else is it's gone
on like a bit of a journey that hasn't
involved me whatsoever
and eventually it ended up in zuma's
hand you know xei zuma via uyad and he's
made a building entirely for tag and
he's been wanting me to sort of cement
the rules in place since i kind of
invented the game for a long time now so
we're gonna head over there and do that
at least we know
that prank is a no-go zone on this
server not when it's so laggy oh there's
the tag building here we are oh it's
beautiful zuma oh it's it's wonderful so
when you get tagged the idea is you have
to come here and put your name down on
the list of people that got tagged so we
can keep track of what's going on
let's see if we can find him hey zuma
finally
chiorion this is a looking fab i love it
thank you i i've spent a tremendous
amount of time and effort i can tell
this is pack filled in this is quite
something
so right i've kind of briefly explained
but this is where if you get tagged you
are obliged to come in and write down
your name correct that's right well more
than just write down your name this is
this is gonna be like a ritual for the
tag game now okay
someone's tagged they've gotta go
through the hoops do a bunch of
challenges and stuff and uh
and also most importantly this building
is to like put the rules of the game
solid in stone and make it easy for
people who want to follow the tactics
yeah no excuses
um but before we go in i guess who is
currently tagged because like it's the
tag game has been off my channel now for
a while and i'm pretty sure people
aren't aware of where we're at
the the game is effectively on hold and
the person who is tagged is uh evil x
that's right evil alter ego
exactly
um
that's whose tags and it's going to be
very interesting when evalex has to try
and tag other hermits you must undertake
this ritual before you play the game of
tag jump through
towers high to take a leap of faith but
first one must be punished and take the
walk of shame oh dear yes
this is your idea yeah this was my idea
to be fair the walk of shame so when you
get tagged you've got to walk through
here you get keep getting splashed by
stuff you keep getting hit
and exactly you get up to the top and
then
[Music]
oh no
so you got to make it all the way to the
top just to be thrown back down
yep all the way under underneath the
building to like the basement
so it goes all the way down here through
the attic
all the way down below and that's the
bit that i'm currently working on now
all right
it's the bottom area this is where
you're gonna see the rules
so each person who's tagged can put a
punishment into the randomizer and a
twist for each round
but they won't get to pick their own one
right it can't so i mean the the things
that are going through my mind right now
like that what are the limitations on
these punishments can i write down you
have to sing your entire episode
like where does it start
let's see why not this is this is like
we're unleashing the creativity
like
is there a line
can they like look at this punishment
and be like no i'm not i'm not doing
this i mean
i think i think that's up to each hermit
right i think we covered just about
everything there
if that's good for you yeah this is
great uh
this is this has become way more than i
thought tag would ever be
but i like it
i like where this is going
that's good because i've taken a lot of
time it needs to it needs to deliver now
you know so now once this is done
evil x is going to be set free
to get someone
well i think we've made a pretty good
amount of progress on this and we're
going to continue this
that's all right well we're going to
continue in a bit so thank you for
showing me around this is going to be
really fun and we're going to brainstorm
some awful i think is the right word
awful punishments for people that get
tagged and it's going to be mischievous
indeed all right see you later then
see you later man and we're off
let's head back to the base we may not
have had a very successful trip on all
of these pranks that we've tried to do
but maybe we can get our own back maybe
we can create some really funny
punishments and stuff for whoever gets
tagged in the future oh the game has
thoroughly thoroughly evolved now i am
so excited to see what happens so
basically to recap this episode i made a
lot of progress on my base look the
towers are in it's now white concrete
it's
it doesn't look like a flower pot or a
blender if you ask me it looks well
looks like a futuristic base
and we also tried to prank mumbo's
little island with a trick that no
longer works if i can find a way to do
it i'm definitely going to do that again
i don't
i'm so i'm so annoyed and then we tried
to prank zuma who caught me in the act
so i had to bail on that one then we
pranked jevin who's still afk to this
moment by the way so when he eventually
gets back well yeah that failed as well
we tried to send him on an afk journey
but the lag got to him pushed him off so
uh we will perhaps come back to that and
next time we're going to put them in a
minecart so that they don't get pushed
off the edge so maybe afk trap mark 2
will happen at some point
oh i'm so disappointed in myself i'm
normally
pretty good at these pranks but it's
been a very difficult couple of days
with what i've been doing so thank you
very much for watching everyone i hope
you enjoyed this episode and i'll see
you in the next one bye
you